# Mike Smith

**Smyrna, GA, 30082** 

Phone: 770.851.0497 | Email: mike@mikeqsmith.com

Website: mikeqsmith.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mikeqsmith

GitHub: github.com/mqsmith

# **Summary**

A Full Stack Web Developer with certification from the University of Georgia, Georgia Institute of Technology, and Harvard University. Experienced professional leader with a 10-year background in live event production and a life-long dedication to continuous learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known among teammates for collaboration and strong attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, JSON, Java

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Next. is, Node, Express, Handelbars, iQuery, Bootstrap, D3,

**Tools**: JIRA, Jenkins, Bitbucket, Rally, github **Database:** MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Cockroach

Applications: Microsoft Office Suite, Google Suite, Final Cut Pro, Photoshop, After Effects, Illustrator,

InDesign, Keynote, Pro Presenter, Pro Video Sync, Pro Video Player

# **Experience**

# SalesVista 2021 to Present Software Developer

Create, maintain, and deploy SaaS using Next.JS and React on the front end while using Node, Express and Cockroach db on the back end. This single page application is a compensation management tool developed to help companies maintain and track sales compensation for all of their sales reps. We make it the data is more accurate and the collection is more efficient and the senior management has more control.

## **Automatic Data Processing (ADP) Associate Application Developer**

2019 to Present

Create, maintain, and deploy multiple Microservices within ADP on-prem infrastructure and to AWS Cloud. The majority of these applications are written in TypeScript, JavaScript, and D3 with a java backend, while following Agile and Scrum methodologies. The resulting products help clients all over the world bring innovative HR processes to their employee populations.

# Passion Productions 2015 to 2019 Technical Director

Led all production aspects, e.g., technology, gear, and team leadership, for the Cumberland location and enterprise events including implementing the vision and culture of Passion City Church within the production team. Ensured internal and external client satisfaction by building relationships, gaining trust and requesting feedback. Launched a new location and set the groundwork for future teams to step into. Cultivated a consistent rotation of volunteers through leadership and motivation, solving a year-long issue for the company. Successfully managed a yearly budget of \$900,000

#### **Technical Coordinator**

Led multiple teams of production contractors to execute events with audio, lighting, video, and performances by managing pre-planning calls, gear rental, and other event preparation.

#### **Freelance Live Event Production**

2009 to 2015

#### **Production Technician**

Served as Producer, Programming Director, Lighting Director, and Lighting Designer. Scheduled and trained volunteer teams on proper implementation and storage of production equipment. Managed and archived all production data.

# **Projects**

#### **Workforce Now**

**Workflow** – a microservice with-in workforce now (WFN)

Description: Developed an all new UI for an older PaaS legacy product. This microservice is used by the majority of WFN clients to setup and enable employee activities such as time off requests, benefits elections, etc.

Technologies Used: TypeScript, React, Java

Deployed using docker on ADP hosted on-prem storage and AWS

Org Chart – a microservice with-in workforce now (WFN)

Description: Developed an all new UI new microservice to offer our WFN clients. This microservice is an organization chart that is using D3.js and JavaScript to create a hierarchical depiction of the organization.

Technologies Used: JavaScript, React, D3, Java

Deployed using docker on ADP hosted on-prem storage and AWS

**Virtulogics** | virtulogics.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/mqsmith/virtulogics

Description: VMware capacity planning simplified. This application takes a clean, simple, straightforward look into your environment to keep you N+.

Technologies used: Mongo, NodeJS, Express, React, JavaScript, Influx, telegraf, Bootstrap, jwt

Dependencies include: mongoose, express, path, doteny, nodemon, redux, jwt, bcrypt

#### **Slap Bet** | mikeqsmith.com/slapbet | github.com/mqsmith/slapBet

Description: A friendly betting app that allowed even the most novice bettor to make educated wagers on their favorite teams

Technologies used: D3, Chart.js, Formspree, Firebase, ajax, Bootstrap, jQuery

## **Education**

Java Certificate: The University of Georgia

A 6 month program focused specifically on mastering Java.

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate: Georgia Institute of Technology

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

### **Introductory Computer Science Certificate:** HarvardX of Harvard University

An 11-week program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Objective-C, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Python & MySQL.

## Bachelor of Arts, Sports Business: University of Georgia

Completed 100/120 hours

### **Personal Interests**

Volunteering at my church on the Production Team Church small group leader/participant Coffee Enthusiast